Well, first of all, I just want to thank
everybody at the the Vikings
organization from first of all the
incredible visit that I had and
everything. And then I got to thank the
Lord and Savior Jesus Christ for, you
know, I I said a long prayer tonight
with with my best friends, my closest of
friends and, you [snorts] know, I thank
my family. Um, my parents are phenomenal
parents. Um, all my teammates in Miami
are, you know, Coach Chrisall, Coach
Harris, Coach Ethridge for taking a
chance on a guy that was a a backup and
and took him to Miami and now he's in
Minnesota. And
I I can't be I can't be more grateful
than than this moment right here. I'm
just I'm super blessed and I just want
everybody to know that you guys got
somebody that's [snorts] that's ready to
go at all moments and all times. He's
going to give his all for everything. U
I'm a Viking for life.
Jacobe, um, congrats first of all.
Welcome to Minnesota. Um, you mentioned
that you had an incredible visit here.
I'm just curious if you can expand a
little bit on like what sort of impacted
you during your time here. Um, you know,
what what kind of helped it to feel like
it would be a good fit for you and just
kind of adds to the emotion of tonight?
>> Absolutely. Um, the biggest thing for me
is I always like to see the environment
of a of a of a workplace. And uh, when I
walked in to to the to the Vikings
facility, um, I had a I had a my
hostess, her name was Milan, and
everybody that walked past each other in
the facility spoke to each other and had
genuine conversations. And it just felt
so family oriented at that place that I
just it it felt so wholesome and and and
warming to be there. Um, I wasn't
stressed or tense. You know, in this in
this situation, you can you can get
there sometimes. And there, I was able
to relax and really just be me because
it's just there's so much humility in
that building and I loved it.
>> Jacobe, just wondering where you feel
you grew the most during that season at
Miami. Like, where did you elevate your
game?
>> Um, [sighs and gasps]
[snorts] just just being comfortable in
who I am again. Um, you know, I had a
rough time you my previous spot and you
know, I had a lot of confidence issues
and you know, coach Harris, my my
safeties coach, uh, we sat long long
long nights a lot of times just talking
about, you know, this moment and getting
to this position. So, I think just
growing as a person and understanding
who I am as a man is is really what got
me here.
>> Jacobe, uh, congratulations. Um, if I'm
not mistaken, the broadcast uh mentioned
your blitzing and then I believe Coach
Oonnell uh mentioned blitzing as well.
Can you maybe uh you know, would you
agree that you know, first off, you're
an effective blitzer? And if so, uh can
you maybe speak to, you know, is this a
speed and timing thing? Is this a
mindset thing? Is this something else?
Um what what goes into this aspect of
your game?
>> Um it's just aggression, man. I have um
you know my my parents have been through
a lot and anytime I line up against
somebody else with an opposite color
jersey on they're taking you know the
food out of my mom's mouth and you know
I I can't let that happen. So anytime I
get the opportunity to blitz or play
football in general I'm playing at 100%
thousand% effort at all times. So I just
say it's just a mindset thing.
Yeah. U Jacobe, first of all, congrats,
man. Um,
what
can you just walk through the process of
you go from again not being a starter to
ending up at Miami? How did they It's
probably a question for them, but like
how did how did that transition happen
for you?
>> Um, sorry, I'm getting a lot of calls
here. I'm so sorry if my camera's going
off.
Um,
you know, I I had a long talk with my
mom. Um, I ended up entering the
transfer portal, not really expecting
much. And Coach Mario Chris called me
and Coach Harris called me and, you
know, they just they didn't sell me a
dream. And, you know, that was the
biggest thing for me is cuz, you know,
recruiting is all it's all smoking
mirrors a lot of the times. And you
know, they took a chance on a kid that,
you know, was four years in college, had
a year left, didn't really play his last
school. So, I don't know what was going
on in their head. I don't know what they
seen and what they thought was, you
know, so good about me. But
that's just that's just credibility to
great coaching and great eyes for
football.
>> Hey, Jacobe, congrats, man. Did you
always think the NFL was possible even
in those moments when you weren't a
starter? And just how much more grateful
does the journey make you now that
you're you have kind of accomplished
this goal?
>> You know, I I always knew the NFL was
possible. Um I lost a little bit of
faith, [snorts] you know, some at some
times, but you know, this moment is just
it it just shows the fact that, you
know, anything is possible if you put
your mind to it. And um I just I don't
even I'm sorry, man. I'm just a lot at a
loss for words for this moment. Do you
guys like my shirt?
>> Looks good.
>> Thank you.
>> Um Jacobe, what what made Cory
Heatherman and that defense special?
Like what what allowed you guys to
transition that thing as successfully as
you guys did?
>> Um you know, first and foremost, Coach
Heatherman is is a phenomenal coach. um
he's he's able to put guys in the
position to win without compromising a
defense. And I think that's what he did
a lot of this year, but you know what
gave us a lot of success was we had a
lot of underdogs on that defense. So, we
had a lot of guys that that had to, you
know, you know, win. And, you know, we
came collectively as a group and we
talked about what our why was to play
football in a summer workout. And we
really had to, you know, we had to tell
the truth. And when you figure out
really what's going on for another guy
across from you at home, that fourth
quarter, that two-minute drive, it it
means so much more at that moment
because you know that there's a lot more
things riding on it than just a loss in
the in the record book.
as it relates to uh your alignment on
the field. I mean, are you a safety
who's going to keep a roof on things
deep down the field? Are you more
comfortable kind of close to line
scrimmage? I know we talked about like
blitzing and obviously that kind of that
kind of um obviously means a little bit
closer, but uh do you shuffle around? Uh
where are you found?
>> Um I'm found in [snorts] whatever
position I need to do for us to win.
That's just who I am. Um,
I I can't I can't specifically say, you
know, I like to be at a specific spot on
the field. I just like to be wherever my
coach puts me, I'm going to do that job
at 100%. And whatever it takes to win,
that's that's how I'm going to get it
done.
>> Jacobe, um, if you talked to Brian
Flores on the visit, what was that
conversation like or what stands out
about your interactions with him or the
defensive staff? Um, you know, coach
coach coach Flores is he's he's a
phenomenal football mind. Um, and I'm a
football addict, so the chance to not
only him teach me, but to really have a
sit down conversation with a guy like
him is it meant everything to me
because, you know, you I'm I'm a
Tennessee guy, man. So, you know,
watching Harrison Harrison Smith up
there is it was it was a moment for me
to see, you know, what could be done
from a for a small town kid. And, you
know, you look at what coach Flores has
done in his past and how he's always
done his defenses, you you really
understand the fact of he this guy
really knows football. And to learn from
a guru in football like him, man, it was
it was just amazing.
>> Jacobe, you called yourself a football
addict. Um, just I guess you know when
did you sort of fall in love with the
sport? What's maybe kind of your your
earliest memory of football or when you
knew that like this was it for you?
>> Um, you know, my mom has a baby picture
of me and it's the first picture she
ever took of me and it was me holding a
football. So I think from the moment
that you know I opened my eyes and
became you know in this world I just
football's always been something that
you know holds so much value in my heart
and there's been so many monumental
moments in my life that have come from
football that you know it just makes me
love the game much more.
>> Oh go ahead Lindsay.
>> Oh just one last one. Um I know you've
mentioned your family a couple times and
just you know how much it it means to
them. I guess what's it like to just
sort of celebrate this with them tonight
and and know how big of a deal this is?
>> Man, it's a moment that you you know you
you dream of as a kid. Um and and then
you get in this moment and it just feels
so much more uh I've had [snorts] my
family's not a lot of blood rel
relatives. So um it's I'm so sorry my
phone is going crazy.
Um,
here we go. I'm sorry. Um, I'm so sorry.
It's a moment that I can't I can't I
can't think enough. Um, the the fact
that I get to enjoy this with my high
school football coach is here. Um, you
know, I I can't even put it into words
that this moment means everything to me
because I know how much everybody in
that room upstairs has put in for me to
get here that I can't I can't thank them
enough.
All
right, Jacobe, we'll let you go
celebrate with your family. Thank you so
much for your time tonight.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you so much. God bless y'all.